Simon Goldin

Simon.Goldin@gmail.com

Experienced Software Engineer - NYC / Remote

Experienced full stack engineer with a focus on the front-end using modern tools and best practices across different industries. Experienced in different processes as well as management and mentoring, with a history of working with non-engineers to bring polished applications and features to customers.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Frontend Engineer

Dashlane

New York, NY October 2019 to Present

Driving core front-end development of web applications and extensions in the internet security field relying on a zero-knowledge architecture.

Leading underlying tools and dependencies including a custom component library (CSS-in-JS, React, TypeScript).

Responsible for making application-wide improvements to code quality, long-term maintenance, and developer experience.

Leading development on the b2b product including zero-knowledge SSO/SCIM authentication.

Defining and circulating best practices across the front-end engineering team; regular code reviewing, mentoring, and holding remote pair-programming sessions with other engineers as well as participating in and leading cross-functional efforts such as design system development.

Primarily working with React and TypeScript, partially involved with CI/CD tools (gitlab) and build processes (yarn/npm).

Working with other stakeholders to iterate on existing processes to allow engineers, designers, and copywriters to improve velocity and visibility.

Engineering Manager November 2021 to April 2022

Managed 5 frontend engineers developing the B2B product, but ultimately decided to return to the technical leadership track.

Senior Full Stack Engineer

January 2018 to October 2019

TripleLift

New York, NY

In addition to responsibilities below: mentorship of other engineers; wrote and discussed technical specifications across the team, improved workflow, processes,

Led a cross-team project to build a customized, reusable, and scalable component library leveraging Material UI (React, TypeScript).

Full Stack Engineer

TripleLift

New York, NY

August 2015 to January 2018

Developed and maintained a variety of applications in AngularJS, React (and TypeScript), PHP, Go, and NodeJS for internal and external users for campaign and

creative management, as well as JS code used on publishers' sites.

Heavily involved in application architecture decisions as well as hiring, code reviews, providing business context to engineers, and technology context to non-engineering teams.

Software Engineer

play2prep New York, NY **August 2013 to July 2015**

Worked with management and designers to develop a test preparation studying mobile app for iOS and Android phones and tablets using Cordova, Grunt, Bower, NPM, AngularJS, SCSS, Java, and Apache Thrift.

Programmer

TMCBonds LLC. New York, NY October 2010 to August 2013

Implemented solutions to improve developer and client user experience. Supported monthly releases; Monitored stability of website supporting \$150M in daily trades. Led development of mobile application using Sencha Touch and

pre-existing Java backend.

and developer experience.

Web Developer Rutgers University

Piscataway, NJ

Helped develop the official Rutgers School of Engineering website and other Drupal-based sites for Rutgers University. Took on system administration roles in a LAMP (PHP) server environment.

January 2009 to October 2010

Web Developer Freelance

April 2007 to August 2015

Developed websites using WordPress, Drupal, vanillaJS and jQuery, as necessary for a particular project. Followed strict deadlines to complete projects to client specifications for small businesses and organizations. Often worked concurrently on multiple websites to create production code from sketches and mockups (PDFs, PSDs, pen & paper, etc).

EDUCATION

Rutgers University School of Engineering New Brunswick, New Jersey Bachelor of Science in Computer and Electrical Engineering, May 2010 Electrical Engineering; Digital Signal Processing, Sensors & Networking Systems.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Languages & Frameworks: React, NodeJS; unit testing with Jest, React Testing Library, others; Emotion, styled-components, CSS-in-JS, LESS & SCSS; HTML5 & CSS3; JavaScript, NPM/Yarn/PNPM, PHP, Java, Go, MySQL, MongoDB.

Software & Tools: Mac OS X, Windows, Linux; debugging tools (Chrome & FireFox DevTools, xdebug); git, gitlab, github; Intellij IDEA/WebStorm, vim; Photoshop, Illustrator; comfortable with sysadmin tasks and command line tools; AWS.